[Melody of Golden Age]
[Episode 23]
Pan?
Why are you here?
Secretary Yan.
Long time no see.
This is a critical investigation area.
How can you just let
irrelevant people in?
Grand Commander, you have misunderstood.
This gentleman
is the top civilian detective,
Pan Chi, Mr. Pan.
He's here to assist me
in the investigation.
He's not an irrelevant person.
Grand Commander Shen.
So it's true.
The rumors are all true.
Pan is indeed Pan Chi.
You can also
always think of that Pan
as just that Pan.
I also happened to come across this case.
I was asked by the suspect's brother-in-law
to come and investigate.
When the suspect was first arrested,
he had nothing on him,
and no weapon was found.
I suspect
he might have been wrongly accused.
The case files mentioned
that the victim's younger brother
is not trained in martial arts.
The probability of the brother committing the crime is very low.
Based on the situation at the victim's home,
it's very likely to be a revenge killing.
The elder brother had a bad temper
and often had disputes over land issues
with the neighbors.
He even got into fights
and caused trouble for the village head.
In his business,
he also often had conflicts with others.
He offended quite a few people.
It's possible that
the killer took this opportunity to murder him
and then frame the victim's younger brother.
If it's a revenge killing,
then the killer and the victim
must have had a deep grudge.
Just killing would be one thing,
but to also take
the victim's head away...
Why would they do that?
Putting aside the motive,
can you two deduce
what kind of weapon was used?
Don't rush, Governor Mo.
Let us examine it carefully.
Let's call it a day.
I'm hungry.
Governor Mo.
I'll take my leave.
[Mortuary]
Didn't you say we'd investigate the case first?
Why are you suddenly hungry?
Besides,
we're not in Xiang'an now.
How come you just...
Anyway, I'm hungry right now.
Didn't you say
you'd make me some medicinal soup?
Where is it?
Make medicinal soup?
Are you sure you want to use these hands?
What's wrong?
These hands just examined a corpse.
The medicinal soup made with these hands,
are you sure you can eat it?
I can eat it.
Just wait.
That's more like it.
Look at him, not even preparing
a welcome feast today.
I was worried
that this stingy Governor Mo
would also mistreat us with the guest rooms.
Jing Lin,
watch your words.
Governor Mo is diligent in his duties and loves the people.
He is known among the common people
as a rare good official.
It's just a welcome feast.
Being able to truly serve the people
is what's most important.
I went to check.
Their kitchen here is quite good.
As soon as Madam returned,
she went to make medicinal soup for you.
Help me carry this.
Kid.
Why is it you?
Your mast...
Where's your sister?
As soon as my sister returned,
I pestered her to teach me skills.
She readily agreed,
but ended up taking me to the kitchen.
She taught me how to cook medicinal soup once,
then hurriedly left
to meet her old friend.
leaving me to watch the pot for two hours.
Her old friend?
Young people in the Yingzhou area are accustomed to living on the vast grasslands.
They hunt outside the city in fox fur robes.
The code is correct.
But why is it a male voice?
This isn't right.
This voice sounds familiar.
How...
It's you?
Young people in the Yingzhou area are accustomed to living on the vast grasslands.
They hunt outside the city in fox fur robes.
Even after drinking a thousand cups of wine, they won't get drunk.
These children of ethnic minorities can ride horses and run freely at a young age.
I am Chi.
Pleased to meet you, Xing.
Chi?
You're clearly a young gentleman.
Why did you lie to me saying you were
a young lady from Jiangnan?
Actually, I didn't mean to deceive you.
It's just that
when you first replied,
you already called me "young lady."
I...
Then who told you to use
a woman's floral stationery?
The letter is fragrant,
with flower petals enclosed.
Young Master.
You said you'd write lyrics for my new song.
It's been over a month now.
When will you write it for me?
I'll write.
[Chi]
Please help me deliver this letter to the Ministry of Justice.
Thank you.
Director Wu.
These are the letters we received
after our public announcement
requesting information on difficult cases
a few days ago.
I've organized them by region,
all sorted out.
The one on top is...
Throw them away, throw them away.
Don't you understand what I'm saying?
Throw them away.
If you're really that bored,
go scrub the floor.
[Ministry of Justice Clue Collection Office for Suspected Cases]
My thoughts on the Ministry of Justice's unsolved cases.
I thought
it was some young lady from Jiangnan
who, like me, enjoyed analyzing cases.
That's why I sent the first reply letter.
This "Chi"
was actually a name I came up with casually.
This flower
was borrowed from someone else.
Then I've been calling you by the wrong gender.
Why didn't you correct me
in your later replies?
Well, I thought about it this way:
Since we're pen pals,
whether I'm a young gentleman
or a young lady,
it doesn't affect our friendship through letters,
discussing various topics,
and exchanging case information.
Don't you agree?
You're right.
When you put it that way,
it does feel more liberating.
Oh, right.
I didn't know what you liked,
so I specifically went to find
[Record of Extraordinary Techniques from the Western Region]
a rare copy of "Record of Extraordinary Techniques from the Western Region."
In this book,
it records
the unique tools and techniques from the Western Region.
Take a look
and see if you like it.
Thank you.
I like it very much.
[Curved Sword]
Wait.
It's this page.
Take a closer look
[Curved Sword]
at the curved knife on this page.
After you left today,
I examined the corpse again.
The wound on the headless corpse,
judging from the angle of the wound
and its smoothness,
it doesn't seem to be caused by a straight blade,
but rather a curved one.
So based on my assessment,
the murder weapon
should be
a specially made curved knife that can cut through iron like mud.
I've seen this type of curved knife
at the border of Xichen.
The curved knife on this page
only has slight differences
[Curved Sword]
in the blade edge compared to
the wound on the victim's neck.
The structure is almost identical.
So whether it's this exact knife
still requires further investigation from us.
Curved sword from the Western Region?
No wonder I've been racking my brains today,
but couldn't figure out
what weapon was used.
It turns out to be something
I've never seen before.
It seems I really need to
study this book carefully.
Learn more about weapons from the Western Region.
Maybe I can even find
some clues in here.
This time I came to Gannan Area,
besides investigating the case,
there's something even more important.
Grand Commander.
Governor Mo is tired today
and has retired early.
It's not convenient to meet.
You should also go back and rest early.
Please convey to Governor Mo
that I'll come another day for a good chat.
I understand.
This way, Grand Commander.
Like a dream, like an immortal, suddenly drifting away.
Where is the evening glow, leaving only the empty green screen?
So,
even before the incident in Xiang'an City,
in the hands of human traffickers in Gannan Area,
there was already the Fire Moth Jade.
That's right.
The Fire Moth Sect's infiltration in Gannan Area
is deep and far-reaching,
far beyond our imagination.
As I've been investigating covertly along the way,
I've discovered that many local people
secretly follow the Fire Moth Sect.
From Xiang'an to Yingzhou,
I always feel that
behind the Fire Moth Sect,
there's an invisible hand
orchestrating a grand scheme.
Moreover, the person behind this plan
must be someone with immense power and influence.
I didn't notice
we've been talking for so long.
It's getting late.
I should head back.
So,
let's chat again next time.
Where's my gift?
You didn't forget to prepare one, did you?
Well, I did prepare something,
but...
It's not really suitable for you.
You definitely won't like it.
Next time,
I'll buy you something
newer.
You haven't even shown it to me.
How do you know whether I like it or not?
You insisted on seeing it yourself.
Alright.
You've seen it.
Are you convinced now?
How can there be a reason
to take back a gift given to someone?
Besides,
I really like it.
I happen to be missing
a hairpin.
So,
why don't you put it on for me yourself?
How is it?
Is it good?
Why did the candle suddenly go out?
Could it be...
It's good, quite good.
It's getting late.
I really should go.
See you.
It's so late.
Are you planning to keep vigil for me?
Why are you still staying there?
Come and rest.
Forget it.
It's not like
we haven't slept in the same bed before.
if I catch a cold,
that would be asking for trouble.
That Pan Chi,
is he really that much to your liking?
What do you mean by "to my liking"?
Oh, you mean the investigation?
We do work well together.
You...
What are you doing?
if you keep this up,
I won't be so polite anymore.
You won't be polite?
I'd like to see
how impolite you can be.
Shen Du,
why aren't you sleeping in the middle of the night?
Have you gone mad?
Someone is beating the drum to appeal for justice.
Who is beating the drum below?
What grievance do you have?
My Lord,
this humble citizen is named Du Fusheng.
I am an herbal medicine merchant.
Today
is the wedding day of my youngest daughter, Du Xiaowan,
to Li Zimou,
son of Li Hongfa.
But something strange and unexpected happened.
My daughter
was still present during the welcoming ceremony,
but after the wedding banquet ended
and it was time for the newlyweds to enter their chamber,
we discovered that she had disappeared.
It happened so suddenly,
and we searched everywhere but couldn't find her.
That's why we've come to report this to the authorities.
On such a joyous day with many guests,
this won't be easy to investigate.
Do you have a guest list?
Yes, yes,
it's right here.
Bring it to me.
Was this marriage between your two families
a mutual agreement?
Of course it was.
Xiaowan and I are well-matched in social status.
We admire each other.
Who could have known something like this would happen?
I beg you, Governor Mo,
please find Xiaowan.
Guards!
Take some men to investigate both households.
Pay special attention to the Li family's house.
Examine it carefully
to see if there are any
traces left behind.
Focus particularly
on the entrances and exits of all areas.
Yes, sir.
Governor Mo,
[Wedding]
we've checked the guest list.
Most of the guests are still here,
only a few are missing.
Find them.
Bring them all back once you've found them.
Yes, sir.
What's the matter?
My Lord,
if we all go out to search for people,
I'm afraid there won't be enough manpower
to investigate the scene.
[Wedding]
Governor Mo,
if there's not enough manpower,
my Imperial Guards can help.
Then I'll trouble you, Grand Commander Shen.
Jing Lin.
Yes.
Go ahead.
Yes, sir.
You all, come with me.
You too, come with me.
Li Hongfa comes from a wealthy family.
The wedding chamber must have been
carefully decorated.
There are no signs of
a struggle inside the room.
[Wedding]
It seems something happened in the wedding chamber,
and in a fit of anger,
someone damaged this place.
[Wedding]
It's supposed to be a joyous occasion,
yet everything here seems strange.
Moreover,
this doorframe clearly
has been renovated,
but there are signs of peeling paint.
There must be something wrong here.
I think so too.
By the way,
did you find anything on your end?
I passed through the living room,
the corner pavilion,
and the rockery.
But along the way,
I didn't find anything suspicious.
That's right.
The bride didn't leave voluntarily.
She was abducted by someone she knew
and taken through the back window.
With such an urgent case at hand,
you two still have the mood
to chat idly here?
Secretary Yan and I are analyzing the case.
How is this idle chat?
Besides,
we've already reached a conclusion.
The bride
was indeed abducted through this back window.
Alright,
now it's time for certain people to get busy.
Quickly give orders to search for the person.
Alright.
Please lead the way, Mr. Pan.
Come with my Imperial Guards
to pursue the suspect.
Why did you leave halfway through the banquet?
A servant came to report
that my child was sick.
My spouse
doesn't know how to take care of the child.
It was already that late;
surely we were not
going to keep that up until dawn?
Prefectural Governor,
about this matter,
please
don't tell my wife.
I just came
to check on my mistress.
During the wedding,
did anything
strange happen?
Not really,
except that
Xu Jize performed exceptionally well.
I didn't notice anything
else unusual.
This Xu Jize,
he really had it tough.
The job of a wedding host
is not easy to begin with.
It's rare for someone from Yingzhou to do this.
But I heard
that he had no one to recommend him
and couldn't find a way to take the exams,
so he ended up becoming a wedding host.
Please, everyone.
What about that Xu Jize?
Why isn't he here?
My Lord,
we couldn't find him.
Couldn't find him?
In that case,
Xu Jize
is the only one who left early
and could have close
contact with the bride.
Secretary Yan,
do you think
the culprit might be Xu Jize?
At this point, I can't answer
your question.
Before the case is solved,
everyone present
is a suspect.
And his absence now
only means
his suspicion is even greater.
In the end,
we still need physical evidence and witness testimony.
As expected of the wife of Grand Commander Shen,
though young in age,
your words and actions are impeccable,
with a set of principles of your own.
From your words, Governor Mo,
it seems you are quite familiar
with my husband?
Take them all back to the Governor's Mansion.
Yes, sir.
Let's go.
[Xu Jize]
Please don't kill me.
Don't kill me, don't kill me.
Who are you?
Why are you fleeing in panic in the middle of the night?
My name is Xu Jize.
Don't kill me. D-Don't kill me.
Over there.
There are dead people over there, over there.
Xu Jize.
You're that wedding host?
Hand him over to Governor Mo.
Well, well, Shen Du.
Throwing an ordinary civilian out there as a roadblock.
Is this how the Imperial Security Bureau operates?
The Imperial Security Bureau's style?
Is it a machine that kills without hesitation,
or a bogeyman that stops children from crying
at night?
Which one
do you prefer?
Grand Commander Shen, I'm impressed by your self-awareness.
I admire you.
Truly admire you.
But since we've come this far,
why don't we speak frankly?
You're constantly targeting me,
finding fault with everything I do.
If that's the case,
why do you insist on dragging me along
to chase after the killer?
Mr. Pan, you also have self-awareness.
Knowing that you're an eyesore to me,
why do you keep showing up?
That's for the needs of solving the case.
I have no choice.
The needs of solving the case?
Seeing me arrive, you escalated your actions.
Is that also out of necessity?
Help!
Why did it go quiet?
You,
go down and check.
Why should I be the one to go down?
You are
the Grand Commander.
Who knows what's happening down there?
Besides,
if I go down
and get killed, what then?
If you die,
I'll collect your body,
build you a tomb,
and make sure your soul
doesn't wander around
scaring people.
-Why are you so mean?
-You can’t beat me, right?
Go down.
I'll go check out the situation first.
You are...
Don't be afraid. I'm here to rescue you.
Grand Commander.
You're the bride from today, aren't you?
[Du Xiaowan]
Yes.
I am Du Xiaowan.
Please save me, My Lord! Please!
There's another person down there.
Another one.
At least you have a conscience.
I climbed up by myself.
My back!
And you call yourself a Grand Commander.
Do you even understand the code of honor?
You've framed me time and time again.
It's not you.
There's another one.
A dead person.
You guys,
go check the surroundings.
Jing Lin,
go see if there's
anything unusual down below.
Yes.
Reporting, Grand Commander.
There are no abnormalities down below.
Grand Commander,
the surroundings have all been checked.
There are no anomalies.
All along the way,
we all saw
that nervous-looking
wedding host suspect.
Why do you still need to investigate repeatedly?
Are you so certain
that this person is not the killer?
I can't be certain
whether that person is the killer or not,
but my intuition tells me
that this matter
is not as simple
as what we've seen.
I must say, I'm truly impressed.
So the esteemed Grand Commander solves cases
based on nothing but
an innate, gifted intuition.
Grand Commander,
shall we continue the investigation?
Let's withdraw.
-Where is she?
-You bastard!
Give me back my daughter!
Where have you hidden her?
Where's Xiaowan?
Answer me!
You beast!
In this court,
you must behave yourself.
Xu Jize,
I ask you,
is the case of Lady Du's disappearance
related to you in any way?
I've been wronged, My Lord!
The abduction of Lady Du
has nothing to do with me.
I only wanted to rescue her.
Do you have any witnesses or evidence
to prove this?
My Lord,
it happened so suddenly.
I was in a hurry to save her.
No one saw what happened.
But every word I say is true.
I beg you to see the truth, My Lord.
So you have no witnesses or evidence then.
Madam,
Grand Commander has returned.
You're finally back.
Did you find anything?
We found the bride.
And we brought back a body.
Someone died?
How about you?
Are you hurt?
I'm not someone who
can be easily injured.
You needn't worry, Honey.
What's wrong with you now?
Why are your hands all wounded?
And there's mud all over you.
You should ask that
clever husband of yours.
All the way here,
I did all the dirty work alone,
and in the end, someone else took all the credit.
Anyway,
it's good that you both
returned safely.
Oh, right,
about the bride,
how did you bring her back?
Tell me the details.
First, on the way,
we encountered
the panicked suspect fleeing.
Then we found
the bride trapped in a cellar well.
In that cellar well,
besides the bride,
there was also a corpse.
So we brought them all back.
The suspect you mentioned,
is he the one the Imperial Guards brought back earlier,
that Xu Jize?
Yes, he's the wedding host.
After you left,
I also investigated
the wedding guests.
According to them, Xu Jize
is a really good person.
On the surface,
he doesn't seem to have a motive for the crime.
Whether he's the culprit or not
still needs to be determined.
Oh, right,
when we were at the bottom of the well,
I remember there was a sack.
That sack
was probably used
to kidnap the bride, right?
Such important evidence,
why didn't you mention it earlier?
I'm not your subordinate.
Why should I
report everything to you?
Alright.
Go change your clothes quickly.
I'll wait for you in the lobby.
This is a matter for the Yingzhou government office.
It should be decided by Governor Mo himself.
I won't go to the hall then.
Sir, you have no evidence.
Yet you've arrested me.
I'm innocent, I tell you!
-I risked my life...
-Where is the trial?
To save Lady Du.
I missed some of it earlier.
-I have no idea.
-And she wasn't hurt.
She just sprained her ankle.
My Lord,
shouldn't you treat me
with a different attitude?
This person really is
good at flattering himself.
Before the evidence is presented,
he completely absolves himself of any wrongdoing.
He even demands respect in court.
It's the first time I've seen
someone so arrogant.
A tree without bark
will surely die.
A shameless person
is unbeatable under heaven.
You're
refusing to believe until you see the coffin, aren't you?
Governor Mo,
I have new evidence to present.
Xu Jize,
does this item
look familiar to you?
This has nothing to do with me.
It must belong to the real culprit.
It was all that dead person
who harmed Lady Du.
I was just there to save her.
Don't wrongly accuse an innocent person!
Then tell us in detail
what you saw.
I...
I just went to the outhouse.
When I came out,
I saw the criminal
kidnapping Lady Du.
It happened so suddenly.
I didn't have time
to notify others.
Worried about Lady Du's safety,
I went to rescue her alone.
You have no proof.
How can anyone believe you?
Heaven and Earth know
that every word I say is true.
I beg you all to see clearly.
Let me help you tell the story.
You and the deceased were accomplices.
You kidnapped Lady Du together.
Then, due to a disagreement,
you killed your accomplice.
To cover up the truth,
you pretended to be a good person.
You shifted all the blame
away from yourself completely.
My Lord.
It's unjust!
I really didn't kill anyone.
I don't even know the deceased.
Why would I have killed him?
When people lie,
they blink constantly
and tend to wrinkle their nose.
But just now when he said
he didn't kill anyone,
his expression was unusually firm.
This suggests he's not lying.
Since you didn't know the deceased,
how did you witness him being killed?
I didn't actually see it
with my own eyes.
When I got there,
the person was already dead.
According to what you're saying,
you saw someone
abduct Lady Du.
Did this person have any distinguishing features?
At that time,
the lighting wasn't very good.
I couldn't see clearly either.
However,
judging from the deceased's height
and demeanor,
it should be
the person who abducted Lady Du.
Just from the height
and demeanor,
didn't you notice
any other characteristics?
It happened so suddenly,
I didn't pay much attention to anything else.
My Lord, Du Xiaowan has arrived.
Wan'er, my Wan'er.
-It's okay.
-Child.
That's enough.
Du Xiaowan,
you are the person involved.
recount everything that happened today,
one by one.
Xiaowan,
we have already performed the wedding ceremony.
You are my wife.
I, Li Zimo, hereby swear to heaven
that I will absolutely not
harbor any resentment because of today's events.
Lady Du,
I know women value their reputation
and it makes it difficult for you to speak up.
But have you considered
if the culprit is not brought to justice,
more young women will
fall victim to this evil in the future?
They might not all be as fortunate as you
to have a chance of rescue.
Honey,
shall we work together to help the Governor Mo
catch the culprit?
What do you say?
After performing the ceremony to heaven and earth,
I met the wedding host in the bridal chamber.
But then,
somehow,
I suddenly fainted.
When I woke up,
I was already inside a sack.
I didn't see who kidnapped me.
I was terrified at that time.
I couldn't even scream.
I only knew that
I was wrapped in a sack,
carried on someone's shoulder as they ran.
After a very long time,
I was finally put down.
Then another person came.
Did you hear
what they were saying?
I thought that person
was coming to rescue me,
but I never expected
that the two of them were actually accomplices.
They were discussing together
how to share me.
The words were truly unbearable to hear.
I really can't bring myself to repeat them.
My Lords,
my wife has suffered such an insult.
I implore you,
to severely punish the culprits.
Rest assured, Mr. Li,
we will not let the perpetrators
escape justice.
Later, I don't know what happened,
but the two of them started arguing.
I made a mistake.
Let's release her.
Are you kidding?
What's done is done.
You have to go through with it whether you like it or not.
I'll go check over there.
After a while,
it seemed like they heard someone chasing from behind.
They then abandoned me in
a cellar well in the ruins.
Before they could even close the cellar cover,
I heard a scream,
followed by a thud.
It seemed like someone
had fallen beside me.
The sack loosened,
and I crawled out.
Help!
I heard someone coming,
but I was afraid it was
the accomplice who had run away earlier.
So I stopped calling for help
until someone
jumped down from the well opening
and rescued me.
Since you've heard them talking,
can you identify by voice
if that person
was Xu Jize?
The situation was critical.
I was terrified.
I was so scared my head was buzzing.
I couldn't make out whose voice it was.
Lady Du has already
made it very clear.
In her last moment before fainting,
she saw Xu Jize.
Whether you're the murderer or not,
this case
is definitely connected to you.
I...
Xu Jize, you bastard!
Bastard!
Beast!
Order!
You beast!
No outbursts in the court!
Madam,
Grand Commander couldn't come in person,
so he sent me to present
the evidence for this case to the court.
There's evidence?
He has a backup plan?
Why wasn't I informed earlier?
I'm not your subordinate.
Why should I report everything to you?
Indeed, his subordinate.
So petty.
Xu Jize,
at this point,
what do you have to say for yourself?
My Lord,
I'm truly innocent.
On the wedding day,
brides often go without food all day
and faint from exhaustion.
It's a common occurrence.
As soon as I saw the bride was unwell,
to avoid suspicion,
I immediately left the room.
Then the thief kidnapped the bride,
and that's when I gave chase.
Still trying to weasel your way out of this?
So what happened after you chased them?
What did you see? Speak.
I don't know how far I chased them.
And then...
Then I saw
a shadowy figure with a knife.
The person who kidnapped Lady Du
had fallen nearby.
As a mere scholar,
I'm weak as a kitten.
I wouldn't dare to confront them.
So I turned and ran,
until I encountered you, My Lords,
only then was my life spared.
My Lord,
what are you doing?
Men and women should not have physical contact.
The embroidery on your clothes, Mr. Xu,
is truly exquisite.
The peach blossom pattern on the collar,
I wonder which young lady
embroidered it for you?